Saumya Sucharita Behera

Professional Summary

Software engineer with 8+ years of experience in design, development, implementation, test, and delivery of enterprise applications in the telecom domain. Seeking Software Engineer roles.

Technical Skills

Languages/Database: Java, Python, Javascript, HTML5, MySQL, Mongo DB

Framework: Spring boot, Django

Software & Tools: Camunda BPM, Spring Tool Suite, VS Code, SOAP UI, Postman, Putty, Git, SVN, JIRA, Rally

Experience

Tech Mahindra Americas Inc

Apr 2016 - Sept 2020

Dallas, TX

Senior Software Engineer (AT&T Virtual Trouble Management)

- \bullet Engineered an integrated ticketing system for $\mathbf{AT\&T}$, expediting trouble management with an $\mathbf{30\%}$ reduction in ticket handling time
- Utilized Spring Boot, Camunda BPM, Apache Kafka, and Mongo DB to create a scalable solution, enhancing user experience and efficiency
- Coordinated onsite and offshore team in India, setting coding standards and conducting peer code reviews, driving productive collaboration
- Managed code deployment on multiple server environments, achieving smooth releases within a Continuous Integration/Continuous Delivery setup

Tech Mahindra Limited

June 2012 - Mar 2016

Pune, India

Software Engineer (AT&T IRU Unlock)

- ullet Improved automation rate for AT&T's device unlocking and network transitioning project from 25% to 80%
- Collaborated with systems engineers to analyze client specifications, aligning project objectives and ensuring accurate design
- Designed, built, and maintained executable workflows in ActiveVOS BPM tool
- Troubleshot and promptly resolved the issues reported by the system testing team, maintaining project timeline
- Produced comprehensive low-level design documentation

Projects

PlanMyMeal | Python, Django, HTML5, Bootstrap Git

July 2023 - Present

- Built a website where users can search for recipes using Spoonacular **REST API** per their nutritional requirements.
- Implemented CRUD operations in **Django ORM** to save recipes with a date on the calendar

Agriculture data analysis | Python, Pandas, Seaborn, Scikit-Learn Git

Aug 2023 – Present

- Determined top agricultural nations using **Linear Regression**.
- Performed Multivariate regression to find a correlation between agricultural production of different countries

Interpreter and parser for a SML like language | Java Git

Feb – Apr 2022

- Used JavaCC tool to generate a pure parser for a SML-like language
- Integrated the evaluator for the expressions comprising the project language to produce a full interpreter

IoT: Smart street lighting system | C++, Arduino IDE, Node-RED, MQTT Git

Nov - Dec 2022

- Collected Photoresistor and infrared motion sensor data using Arduino code and published to MQTT broker
- Node-red flow listened to MQTT messages and controlled the LED if ambient light intensity decreased below threshold or motion was detected.

Education

Villanova University, Pennsylvania

2021 - 2023

Master of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.89/4

Coursework: Algorithms, Database Systems and Health Informatics, IoT, Machine Learning

Biju Patnaik University of Technology, India

2007 - 2011

Bachelors of Technology in Information Technology

GPA: 8.14/10

Certifications & Achievements

SAFe 4 Agilist

Upsilon Pi Epsilon (UPE) honor society: Issued by Villanova UPE Chapter (Apr 2023)

Graduate Assistant at Villanova University: Tutor CS grad students